<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Various Contrivances</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Various Contrivances</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference management</title>
      <link>/2003/11/23/reference-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2003/11/23/reference-management/</guid>
      <description>I have been working through my references and papers trying to regain some control over the literature. Being reintroduced to the tedium of reference management, it seems like there must be a better way to catalogue and organize this important component of research. Ideally, with the Internet and some good citation support from publishers, I would never have to type a citation &amp;#8212; just automagically download whatever I need. Obviously this is not currently available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seed set of dichogamous plants</title>
      <link>/2003/11/19/seed-set-of-dichogamous-plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2003/11/19/seed-set-of-dichogamous-plants/</guid>
      <description>Description:
 These data are the average seed set estimates for dichogamous and adichogamous Chamerion angustifolium at different inflorescence sizes.  Format:
 maternalID: Identification code for the maternal plant (i.e., grandmother of the counted seeds). individualID: Identification code of the plant. array#: The array identification number. dichogamyType: Indicates if the plant was dichogamous. flowerPosition: Flowers were sampled from either the bottom or top of the inflorescence. inflorescenceSize: The number of open flowers on each plant in the array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecology Division Seminar Series, University of Calgary</title>
      <link>/2003/11/12/ecology-division-seminar-series-university-of-calgary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2003/11/12/ecology-division-seminar-series-university-of-calgary/</guid>
      <description>Routley, M.B. The evolutionary significance of being one gender at a time. Ecology Division Seminar Series, University of Calgary
Download http://public.me.com/mroutley/files/Calgary2003.pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pollen deposition after single bee visits in the field</title>
      <link>/2003/09/04/pollen-deposition-after-single-bee-visits-in-the-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2003/09/04/pollen-deposition-after-single-bee-visits-in-the-field/</guid>
      <description>Description:
 These data are pollen counts from stigmas after single bee visits in populations of Chamerion angustifolium from Montana. Pollen was quantified with a Beckman-Coulter Multisizer 3 particle counter.  Format:
 Ploidy: The cytotype of sampled plant, either tetraploid or diploid. AntherPresence: Some flowers had their anthers removed with forceps. Others were left intact. PollenCount: The estimated amount of pollen deposited on the stigma.  Citation:
  PhD thesis MRoutleyThesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siring success of dichogamous plants</title>
      <link>/2003/09/04/siring-success-of-dichogamous-plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2003/09/04/siring-success-of-dichogamous-plants/</guid>
      <description>Description:
 These data are the average siring-success estimates for dichogamous and adichogamous Chamerion angustifolium. Siring success is estimated from the proportion of heterozygous progeny produced at the PGI locus. Dichogamy classes were homozygous for alternate PGI alleles, so that heterozygous progeny represent interclass pollen transfer.  Format:
 Array: The array identification number. DichogamyType: The dichogamy status of the plants in the array. FlowerSize: The number of open flowers on each plant in the array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pollen removal after single bee visits in the field</title>
      <link>/2003/09/03/pollen-removal-after-single-bee-visits-in-the-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2003/09/03/pollen-removal-after-single-bee-visits-in-the-field/</guid>
      <description>These data are pollen counts from anthers before and after single bee visits in populations of Chamerion angustifolium from Montana. Pollen was quantified with a Beckman-Coulter Multisizer 3 particle counter.  Format:
 Population: The population sampled, either tetraploid or diploid. Sample: An identification code representing the plant and flower sampled. StigmaPresence: Some flowers had their stigma and style removed with forceps. Others were left intact. Visitation: Whether the anther was sampled before or after a single bee visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floral Integration</title>
      <link>/2003/07/11/floral-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2003/07/11/floral-integration/</guid>
      <description>Unrelated to my &amp;#8220;official&amp;#8221; thesis work, I have been thinking about floral form and its influence on plant fitness. As an excuse to start a discussion with anyone interested, I&amp;#8217;ve posted this overview of what I hope to work on next.
Plant mating systems control the transmission of genes between generations and, therefore, are a fundamental characteristic of populations. Since flowers are the reproductive organs of plants, floral form fundamentally influences plant mating systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>  &#34; /  June 3, 2003, 12:00 am #  Society for the Study of Evolution meetings 2003Routley, M.B. &amp;amp; B.C. Husband. Responses to selection on protandry in Chamerion angustifolium (Onagraceae). Chico, California
Download
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  January 9, 2004, 10:24 am #  Character assignments in phylogenetic analysesIn some recent research (http://public.me.com/mroutley/SIandDichogamy.pdf) I had to make inferences about families based on character states of the species within the family. One approach is to use a simple majority rule. For example, if more than half of the species possess character state x rather than y, then the family can be described as x.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  April 14, 2004, 6:39 am #  Dynamic State Variable Models in EcologyThere&amp;#8217;s a powerful approach to modelling called dynamic state variable programming, covered in Dynamic State Variable Models In Ecology by Clark &amp;amp; Mangel. I&amp;#8217;ll post more about the approach sometime, but for now I wanted to make an example from the book available. The first chapter of the book includes a guide through the creation of a patch foraging model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>  &#34; /  June 3, 2004, 12:47 pm #  Society for the Study of Evolution meetings 2004Routley, M.B., L.D. Harder, &amp;amp; S.A. Richards. Ovule fates. Colorado State University
Download SSE2004.pdf
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  September 29, 2004, 10:29 am #  The Crusade Against EvolutionAn interesting read from Wired News &amp;#8212; The Crusade Against Evolution. In addition, the Panda&amp;#8217;s thumb has been following and carefully dissecting the recent controversy over an intelligent design paper being published in a peer-reviewed journal. The evolution-creation debate seems to be resurfacing after a short time off. The debate is important and the intelligent design supporters have to be countered, but their arguments have become hackneyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>  &#34; /  October 20, 2004, 12:46 pm #  Ecology Retreat, University of CalgaryRoutley, M.B. Measuring the male gain curve. Ecology Retreat, University of Calgary
Download
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  November 18, 2004, 9:23 am #  Google ScholarYet another useful site from Google: Google Scholar. The site provides an interface for searching the scientific literature with typical Google ease. Some preliminary tests suggest that it is quite effective at finding relevant literature.
 November 7, 2004, 5:33 am #  JSTOR import scriptI&amp;#8217;ve written a script that imports a JSTOR citation page into BibDesk. To use the script, I suggest adding it to your script menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  December 11, 2004, 12:00 am #  Climate change and public relationsA recent column in the Globe &amp;amp; Mail reminded me of our Federal Government’s plan for reducing greenhouse gas emissions: the One Tonne Challenge.
This campaign challenges each Canadian to reduce their contribution to greenhouse gas emissions by one tonne. The first step is to calculate your emissions and then implement recommendations for reductions. According to the online calculator, Kelly &amp;amp; I combined emit 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  January 29, 2005, 10:13 am #  Quirks &amp;amp; QuarksQuirks &amp;amp; Quarks is the CBC&amp;#8217;s excellent science program. I usually download the mp3 archives of the show on the weekends and listen while I walk Ceiligh.
Of course, loading up the Quirks &amp;amp; Quarks webpage, finding the archives, downloading the mp3s, and adding them to iTunes takes at least a few minutes. Computers are much better and handling such tedium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>  &#34; /  March 14, 2005, 10:15 am #  Podcasting &amp;amp; the CBCThe CBC has begun an experiment with podcasting. I&amp;#8217;m impressed with the progressive approach to technology that the CBC has adopted and hope they expand the experiment to more of their programs.
This has the added effect of making my Quirks &amp;amp; Quarks download script obsolete.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  April 14, 2005, 12:27 pm #  Image uploadsA particular challenge with maintaining a weblog is the uploading and resizing of images. The process involves choosing the correct images, creating large &amp;amp; thumbnail sized versions, uploading these images to the webserver, and posting the appropriate code into the weblog post. In the spirit of my last few posts, image2web is an applescript I use to automate this process:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  June 13, 2005, 6:40 am #  Vector assignment in RAs I use R for data analysis and simulations, I become more comfortable and proficient with the R/S syntax and style of programming. One important insight is the use of vector assignments in simulations. I have often read that using such assignments is the preferred method, but until recently I had not realised the importance of this statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  August 19, 2005, 12:25 pm #  The Onion on Intelligent Falling theoryThe Onion on Intelligent Falling theory: &amp;#8220;David Pescovitz: The Onion brilliantly parodies Intelligent Design believers:
KANSAS CITY, KS—As the debate over the teaching of evolution in public schools continues, a new controversy over the science curriculum arose Monday in this embattled Midwestern state. Scientists from the Evangelical Center For Faith-Based Reasoning are now asserting that the long-held &amp;#8216;theory of gravity&amp;#8217; is flawed, and they have responded to it with a new theory of Intelligent Falling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  September 28, 2005, 6:35 am #  Intelligent design in the classroomNow that intelligent design is back in the Canadian news, we should consider (again!) the consequences of teaching intelligent design in the classroom.
Intelligent design makes two postulates:
 Complexity cannot be explained by science.
 Given 1, complexity comes from an intelligent designer.
  Now, consider a science exam in any subject and the danger of intelligent design being taught in school becomes apparent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  October 28, 2005, 6:36 am #  iTunes remote controlThe current setup at home is that I&amp;#8217;ve added all of our music (several thousand songs) to our Mac Mini and then send it through AirTunes to the home stereo. The complication is that the stereo and computer are at opposite ends of the house. Ideally, I can use my iBook to control the Mac Mini without needing to walk down the hall, but how?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  December 24, 2005, 11:39 am #  Idealized, Inaccurate but Successful-- A Pragmatic Approach to Evaluating ModelsJay Odenbaugh provides an interesting article entitled: Idealized, Inaccurate but Successful: A Pragmatic Approach to Evaluating Models. He describes why models are useful to ecologists, even when they are clearly wrong.
 December 24, 2005, 11:38 am #  Robert F. Kennedy, Jr. Sierra Club SpeechRobert F. Kennedy, Jr. gave a speech at the Sierra Club&amp;#8217;s National Convention and Expo on September 10, 2005 in San Francisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  January 16, 2006, 11:36 am #  The Globe and Mail-- Constitutional reformHow about a constitutional right to a healthy environment?
 The Constitution of Canada guarantees its people important rights, such as freedom of religion, freedom of expression, fair trials, free elections, and language rights. But the effective exercise of these rights is impossible without safe water to drink, wholesome food to eat, and clean air to breathe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  February 24, 2006, 11:38 am #  Rails, sqlite3, and id=0I’ve spent the last few days struggling with a problem with Plantae’s rails code. I was certain that code like this should work:
class ContentController &amp;lt; ApplicationController def new @plant = Plant.new(params[:plant]) if request.post? and @plant.save redirect_to :action =&amp;gt; &#39;show&#39;, :id =&amp;gt; @plant.id else ... end end def show @plant = Plant.find(params[:id]) end ... end  These statements should create a new plant and then redirect to the show method which sends the newly created plant to the view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  March 27, 2006, 12:00 am #  Managing project filesAs I accumulate projects (both new and completed), the maintenance and storage of the project files becomes increasingly important. There are two important goals for a file structure: find things quickly and don’t lose anything. My current strategy is as follows:
Every project has a consistent folder structure:
|-- analysis |-- data |-- db |-- doc |-- fig `-- utils  analysis holds the R source files of the analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  April 20, 2006, 10:55 am #  Google calendarGoogle Calendar has been featured in the news recently, and for good reason. Many of us have wanted access to a good online calendar program. One of my favourite features of Google Calendar is its integration with Gmail. If Gmail detects an event in your email message, a link appears that sends the information to Google Calendar. This is incredibly convenient and, seems to me, is one of the great promises of computers: reducing the tedious work that occupies much of our day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  May 24, 2006, 12:35 pm #  Heart of the MatterCBC&amp;#8217;s Ideas has been running a series of shows on heart disease called &amp;#8220;Heart of the Matter&amp;#8221;. Episode 2 is particularly interesting from a statistical perspective, as the episode discusses several difficulties with the analysis of drug efficacy. Some highlights include:
Effect sizes Some of the best cited studies for the use of drugs to treat heart disease show a statistically significant effect of only a few percentage points improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>  &#34; /  June 7, 2006, 3:41 pm #  Burning your moneyBurning our money by Marc Jaccard is a useful overview of some policy options for reducing greenhouse gas emissions. Unfortunately, this article is part of the Globe&amp;#8217;s subscribers-only section, but his paper, Burning Our Money to Warm the Planet, is available from the CD Howe Institute.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  July 12, 2006, 12:30 pm #  The Canary Project-- Global Warming Documented in PhotosThe Canary Project is an intriguing idea. They are documenting the effects of global warming through pictures. Since many people, apparently, don&amp;#8217;t believe the abundant scientific evidence, perhaps some startling pictures will be convincing.
read more | digg story
 July 11, 2006, 12:31 pm #  RSiteSearchI&amp;#8217;m not sure how this escaped my notice until now, but @RSiteSearch@ is a very useful command in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  September 19, 2006, 2:31 pm #  Principles of Technology AdoptionChoosing appropriate software tools can be challenging. Here are the principles I employ when making the decision:
Simple: This seems obvious, but many companies fail here. Typically, their downfall is focussing on a perpetual increase in feature quantity. I don’t evaluate software with feature counts. Rather, I value software that performs a few key operations well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  October 31, 2006, 12:00 am #  Stern Review on the economics of climate changeThe Stern Review has been in the news recently for predicting that global warming could cost up to $7 trillion if not addressed soon. Of course, this has caused quite a stir as it offsets many of the, likely unfounded, concerns that fixing climate change will cost too much. The full report is available online and should be a quite interesting, if long, read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  November 30, 2006, 5:28 pm #  Plantae&amp;#039;s continued developmentPrior to general release, plantae is moving web hosts. This seems like a good time to point out that all of plantae&amp;#8217;s code is hosted at Google Code. The project has great potential and deserves consistent attention. Unfortunately, I can&amp;#8217;t continue to develop the code. So, if you have an interest in collaborative software, particularly in the scientific context, I encourage you to take a look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  January 31, 2007, 12:00 am #  Stikkit-- Out with the mental clutterI like to believe that my brain is useful for analysis, synthesis, and creativity. Clearly it is not proficient at storing details like specific dates and looming reminders. Nonetheless, a great deal of my mental energy is devoted to trying to remember such details and fearing the consequences of the inevitable “it slipped my mind”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  February 19, 2007, 12:00 am #  DabbleDBMy experiences helping people manage their data has repeatedly shown that databases are poorly understood. This is well illustrated by the rampant abuses of spreadsheets for recording, manipulating, and analysing data.
Most people realise that they should be using a database, the real issue is the difficulty of creating a proper database. This is a legitimate challenge. Typically, you need to carefully consider all of the categories of data and their relationships when creating the database, which makes the upfront costs quite significant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  March 30, 2007, 12:53 pm #  Creationists and their old tricksTVO&amp;#8217;s The Agenda had an interesting show on the debate between evolutionary biology and creationism. Jerry Coyne provided a great overview of evolution and a good defence during the debate.
The debate offered a great illustration of the intellectual vacuity that characterises creationism (aka intelligent design). Paul Nelson offers up an article by Doolittle and Bapteste as proof that Darwinism is unravelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  June 23, 2007, 12:00 am #  Stuck in the middleA recent press release from the federal government entitled &amp;#8220;Making a Strong Canadian Economy Even Stronger&amp;#8221; contains a sentence that struck me as odd.
As a result of actions taken in Budget 2007, Canada&amp;#8217;s marginal effective tax rate (METR) on new business investment improved from third-highest in the G7 to third-lowest by 2011. Fair enough, tax rates are projected to decline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  January 6, 2008, 12:00 am #  David Allen: Getting Things Done (via Google)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  April 4, 2008, 12:00 am #  Merlin Mann on Time and Attention (Getting Things Done) (via googletechtalks)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  May 28, 2008, 9:21 am #  
Kelly and I are very happy to announce the arrival of Owen Bruce Routley. He arrived Tuesday morning just after four weighing a solid 8lbs 8ozs.
Although there were some challenges with the delivery, both Owen and Kelly are recovering well and should be home later this week.
We&amp;#8217;ll be posting photos to http://www.flickr.com/photos/mroutley/ for anyone interested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  July 29, 2008, 3:04 pm #  &amp;ldquo;Unfortunately, it’s all pure bunk. To get serious about energy policy, America needs to abandon, once and for all, the false promise of the hydrogen age.&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash; The New Atlantis &amp;#160;» The Hydrogen Hoax July 29, 2008, 10:48 am #  Bridges Still Crumble, a Year After the I-35 Disaster - The Lede - Breaking News - New York Times Blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  August 7, 2008, 8:20 am #  &amp;ldquo;Is it really good for future generations - the alleged beneficiaries of this deluded parsimony - to pass down a clapped out wreck of a town in need of major repairs and upgrades, long-deferred works that become more expensive with every minute they are neglected?&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash; globeandmail.com: Debt free in a clapped out wreck of a town August 6, 2008, 5:13 pm #  &amp;ldquo;Only when significant numbers of people lived downtown, planners believed, could central cities regain their historic role as magnets for culture and as a source of identity and pride for the metropolitan areas they served.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  September 19, 2008, 12:23 pm #  A New Bank to Save Our Infrastructure - The New York Review of Books
A proposal to create a new institution to fund and co-ordinate infrastructure investments.
 September 18, 2008, 8:43 am #  Dan Gardner . Harper economics
Dan Gardner interviews Harvard University economist Gregory Mankiw on climate change economics. The article is an interesting description of the differences between cap-and-trade and carbon tax policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  October 15, 2008, 1:02 pm #  
Fantastic photos of the Sun, via The Big Picture
October 15, 2008, 12:35 pm #  The Food Issue - An Open Letter to the Next Farmer in Chief
Michael Pollan describes the upcoming food crisis in an open letter to the next President of the United States.
 This, in brief, is the bad news: the food and agriculture policies you’ve inherited — designed to maximize production at all costs and relying on cheap energy to do so — are in shambles, and the need to address the problems they have caused is acute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  November 4, 2008, 1:15 pm #  Download audio file
Yesterday I would have ranked country music as one of my least favourites. Now, thanks to CBC Radio 3, I&amp;#8217;m a big fan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  December 24, 2008, 8:42 am #  &amp;ldquo;This country has an immense opportunity to reinvent itself with this budget and transform itself into a “green economy.” But if this metamorphosis is to take place, the budget cannot contain a bunch of giveaways to industry wrapped up in a nice green bow. Instead, it needs to hand out gift certificates with green strings attached that will help Canada&amp;#8217;s economy grow while protecting its natural capital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  January 31, 2009, 1:09 pm #  &amp;ldquo;So 2009 will be a squalid year, a planetary hostage situation surpassing any mere financial crisis, where the invisible hand of the market, a good servant turned a homicidal master, periodically wanders through a miserable set of hand-tied, blindfolded, feebly struggling institutions, corporations, bureaucracies, professions, and academies, and briskly blows one&amp;#8217;s brains out for no sane reason.&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash; Seed: 2009 Will Be a Year of Panic January 30, 2009, 9:17 am #  &amp;ldquo;The Arab states invest their oil fortunes in the craziest things, from the proposed Mile-High Tower in Jiddah to the indoor ski resort in dry-as-dust Dubai.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  February 27, 2009, 12:15 pm #  &amp;ldquo;If you&amp;#8217;ve ever played &amp;#8216;Chinese whispers&amp;#8217;, what comes out the end is usually gibberish, and more or less when we speak to each other we&amp;#8217;re playing this massive game of Chinese whispers. Yet our language can somehow retain its fidelity.&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash; BBC NEWS | Science &amp;amp; Environment | &amp;#8216;Oldest English words&amp;#8217; identified February 25, 2009, 1:48 pm #  Death Sentences ReviewDeath Sentences by Don Watson is a wonderful book &amp;#8212; simultaneously funny, scary, and inspiring &amp;#8212; that describes how &amp;#8220;clichés, weasel words, and management-speak&amp;#8221; are infecting public language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  March 26, 2009, 9:30 am #  globeandmail.com: Natives, Bay Street form country&amp;#039;s biggest farm
 &amp;#8230; in Saskatoon today, Bay Street investors and a group of chiefs from Saskatchewan and Alberta will formally announce the unlikeliest of marriages, one that will make them the most influential farmers in all of Canada, with a super-sized one-million-acre operation that could rival the largest corporate farms in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  May 28, 2009, 12:05 pm #  
The kids have a great time together, which is fantastic.
May 27, 2009, 12:22 pm #  TheStar.com | World-beating bureaucrats
 My research compared the achievements of Canadian public service and political leaders with their U.K. counterparts, and the results are very favourable to Canada. It was rewarding to hear so many U.K. public service leaders ask about Canadian reforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  June 30, 2009, 8:12 pm #  Arthur Benjamin&amp;#8217;s formula for changing math education (via TEDtalksDirector)
June 24, 2009, 10:47 am #  Instapaper Pro 2.0 released!
Excellent. This is one of my top three iPhone Apps and these look like important changes.
 June 21, 2009, 3:12 pm #  John Hodgman at Radio &amp;amp; TV Correspondents&amp;#8217; Dinner (via CSPAN)
June 21, 2009, 11:40 am #  Canada LEED projectsThe CaGBC maintains a list of all the registered LEED projects in Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  July 31, 2009, 8:37 am #  
Owen&amp;#8217;s enjoying the trip.
July 24, 2009, 4:12 pm #  &amp;ldquo;But using federal dollars for infrastructure has two powerful political advantages. It gives taxpayers something tangible for their money. And it allows cabinet ministers and government backbenchers to fan out across the country, announcing local projects.&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash; TheStar.com | Opinion | Cash may never be converted into construction  July 24, 2009, 12:53 pm #  &amp;ldquo;Earlier in the 20th century, governments treated public money with the same puritanical respect that people generally treated their own money in a famously frugal age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  August 13, 2009, 11:15 am #  
On our ferry trip across to PEI, we caught the attention of the boat&amp;#8217;s captain. He was kind enough to let us visit the bridge and take some photos. The setup is pretty amazing, with many radar screens and blinking devices, but all offset by a tiny steering wheel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  September 14, 2009, 12:07 pm #  Is Canada broken?
 “We are in a continuous election campaign with no discussion of issues,” observes Ned Franks, a political scientist at Queen&amp;#8217;s University and a leading authority on Canada&amp;#8217;s Parliament.
 If an election is called, I&amp;#8217;d really like to ignore it, right up to the very end. But, I know I&amp;#8217;ll be reviewing all of the platforms, reading plenty of commentary, and arguing about the issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  October 31, 2009, 12:47 pm #  &amp;ldquo;Now, people waiting in queues will be questioned about why they are there - their likely response being that the health authorities have for months urged them to be there and indeed initially opened clinics to all. If they don&amp;#8217;t fall into one of the risk groups, they will be weeded out. The Public Health Agency of Canada, and other health authorities, along with their political masters, should not be surprised by the resulting public fury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  November 26, 2009, 6:47 am #  Download audio file
Interesting discussion with philosophy professor Mark Rowlands. The first third on the differences between humans, dogs, and wolves, and the last third on perceptions of time are particularly good.
November 24, 2009, 8:36 pm #  &amp;ldquo;Thank goodness for civil servants who breach the walls of government secrecy and obfuscation and speak out for principle, knowing they will be subject to public attack by their very powerful employer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  December 29, 2009, 8:11 pm #  &amp;ldquo;Our current response to terrorism is a form of “magical thinking.” It relies on the idea that we can somehow make ourselves safer by protecting against what the terrorists happened to do last time.&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash; Is aviation security mostly for show? - CNN.com (via Instapaper) December 29, 2009, 8:35 am #  &amp;ldquo;International human rights, it seems, are something the US Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit stands ready to impose on others, but not on ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  January 31, 2010, 11:01 am #  &amp;ldquo;Secretly, I suspect, we technologists quite liked the idea that Normals would be dependent on us for our technological shamanism. Those incantations that only we can perform to heal their computers, those oracular proclamations that we make over the future and the blessings we bestow on purchasing choices.&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash; Future Shock (via Instapaper) January 29, 2010, 1:27 pm #  &amp;ldquo;In the New World, computers are task-centric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  February 27, 2010, 12:23 pm #  
Meeting Baby Caitlynn
February 10, 2010, 10:24 am #  &amp;ldquo;Science is not a cold body of facts, but an organized system of inquiry, discovery, evaluation and learning. Science not only welcomes the correction of errors, its key attribute is that it is self-correcting over time. As new research arises, old hypotheses gain or lose support. While this process never stops, generally accepted conclusions do accumulate, based on the overwhelming weight of evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  March 30, 2010, 7:33 pm #  Peter Gabriel &amp;amp; Bon Iver
March 21, 2010, 2:33 pm #  Important presentation on ecology and agriculture Dan Barber: How I fell in love with a fish (via TEDtalksDirector)
March 19, 2010, 11:41 am #  &amp;ldquo;The previous prime minister was called Mr. Dithers because Paul Martin could never make up his mind. Stephen Harper, it seems, can&amp;#8217;t stop changing his.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>  &#34; /  April 24, 2010, 10:05 am #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  May 11, 2010, 9:23 am #  Snake Oil? The scientific evidence for health supplements
May 10, 2010, 8:51 pm #  Mother&amp;#8217;s Day Brunch</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  June 30, 2010, 6:57 am #  &amp;ldquo;So what we have is a federal government that keeps asserting assumptions that almost all experts think are wrong, that says its critics in the PBO are wrong without providing alternative information, that backs a policy that those who know about such matters are almost unanimous in saying will not work, and that will be spending money on it when most other programs will be cut – all in the politically popular name of being “tough on crime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  July 21, 2010, 9:25 pm #  &amp;ldquo;How in the world did we get to the point that filling out the long form census is just too much to ask? I frankly cannot remember if I, personally, have ever had to do the long form. I’m old enough that I probably did and I hate forms enough that I may have blocked it from memory – but it simply cannot be too great a price to pay for being a Canadian citizen and helping to ensure that all citizens share in its benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  August 30, 2010, 1:04 am #  Todd Houston, Ironman
August 28, 2010, 8:27 pm #  Smoothies
August 26, 2010, 7:06 pm #  Lake Okanagan
August 26, 2010, 5:42 pm #  Airplane</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  October 31, 2010, 8:54 pm #  Halloween 2010
October 27, 2010, 6:56 am #  &amp;ldquo;Toronto’s newly elected mayor identified that anger and the anxiety. Rob Ford fed into it and preyed on it, telling voters in the simplest terms possible that the current crop of politicians were to blame for all their problems, that there were easy solutions that required no sacrifices, that soon they would be able to pay less to their government and get better services in return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>&#34; /  December 6, 2010, 6:38 pm #  &amp;ldquo;Last, there should be appointed a Minister of Opportunity Costs, whose sole responsibility would be to remind his colleagues around the cabinet table that nothing is free, that to favour one industry is to penalize every other. No doubt they will be astonished to hear it. Every single time.&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash; A grasping riot of mutual pocket-pickers - Andrew Coyne - Macleans.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>